僕は運命って言葉が嫌いだ
生まれ　出会え　分かれ
成功と失敗　人生の幸　不幸
I hate the word "fate."
それらが予め運命によって決められているのなら
Birth, encounters, partings,
僕たちは何のために生まれてくるんだろう
success and failure,
fortune and misfortunes in life.
裕福な家庭に生まれる人
美しい母親から生まれる人
If our lives are already set in stone by fate,
飢餓や戦争の真っ只中に生まれる人
then why are we even born?
There are those born to wealthy families,
それらが全て運命だとすれば
those born of beautiful mothers,
神様ってやつはとんでもなく理不尽で残酷だ
and those born into the middle of war or poverty.
あの時から　僕たちには未来なんてなく
If that's all caused by fate, then God is incredibly unfair and cruel.
ただきっと何者にも成れないってことだけははっきりしってたんだから
Because, ever since that day, none of us had a future
and the only certain thing was that we wouldn't amount to anything.
くるくる回る
君の瞳探して回る
駅のホーム
響くファンファーレ
ガラガラ音を立てる街
とりあえず耳を貸してみたの
もうすぐ消えるはずの世界に
御免ね
もう二度と会えないようなそんな気がして
運命が笑う
臨界点突破してる
限界なら既に去って
絶対的支配だって
崩壊
終末理論は机上の空論でしかないって
ゼロとイチの世界線の果てから
叫ぶよ
もうすぐ君が会いにくるような気がして
僕は目を閉じるよ
本字幕由諸神字幕組製作，僅供交流學習，禁止用於商業用途
更多中日雙語字幕，請登錄www.kamigami.org
日聽：xHunter  日翻：Justin   校對：太陽
時間軸：在端涯   壓制：呆狼
よし
All right.
冠葉　ひまり
Kanba, Himari! Breakfast is ready!
朝ご飯出来たよ
Kanba
Shouma
Himari
Takakura
いただきます
Let's eat!
おお　今日の朝飯頑張ったな
Whoa, you've put a lot of effort into today's breakfast!
美味しい
Delicious!
うまいか　ひまり
You like it, Himari?
うん　熱々の味噌汁なんて久しぶりだもん
Yes! It's been a while since I've had hot miso soup.
Oh, right. Soup was always cold when it got to you in the hospital.
そうか
病院のはいつも冷めてたもんな
うん　でも　それより
Yes, but aside from that, your miso soup
tastes just like mom's. That's why I love it.
晶ちゃんの味噌汁　御母さんのと同じ味がする　だから
ひまり
Himari!
だよな
Yeah!
晶馬は近所のスーパーの特売日全部暗記してるしさあ
Shoma memorized all the discounts in the nearby supermarket for every day of the week.
You'll be a great husband!
晶ちゃんはいいおむっこさんになるね
そうかな
You think?
そうだ　この卵焼きもうまいぞ
Yeah, these eggs are great too!
晶馬に秘伝のレシピを教えたら　超ジューシになってさあ
I gave him my secret recipe, and they turned so juicy!
テレビのレシピをやらせただけじゃ
You just made me follow a recipe shown on TV.
俺がお前にテレビを見ろって言ったんだから　同じだろう
I told you to watch TV, so it's the same thing!
秘伝はないよな
Nothing secret about it, then?
いいや　秘伝だ
No, it's a secret recipe.
何故なら　俺はテレビでは言ってなかった舐めるラー油を入れろっていっただろ
Why? Because I told you to put chili oil, which wasn't from TV.
あれは俺のアイデアだ
That was my idea.
どうだ　驚いただろう
What do you think? Wasn't that a great idea?
Shouma - To'oh Hospital - Examination Room
* The brothers receive the sad news from the doctor. If it's fate, that's too cruel.
兄弟が医者から受けた悲しい宣告
運命だとしたらそれはあんまりじゃない
まことに残念ですが
It's very unfortunate, but there's nothing we can
do for her with modern medical technology now.
現代医療の力がもはやどうにも
妹さんの余命はよくもって数か月　あるいは
Your sister has, at best, few months to live.
Possibly even...
そんな
No way.
Bullshit...
ふざけんな　ふざけんな
That's bullshit!
それが医者の言うセリフかよ
Is that something a doctor would say?!
Kanba!
冠葉
I'll get the money somehow!
金ならなんとかする
日本でだめなら　海外で手術させればいい
If she can't get the surgery in
Japan, we can send her overseas!
必要の臓器があれば　俺のを使え
If she needs an organ transplant, she can use mine!
だから
So...
もう何も出来ないなんて言うなよ
Please don't say there's nothing you can do.
言わないでくれよ
冠葉
Kanba...
助けってやてください
Please save her!
どんな犠牲でも払う
I'll do whatever it takes.
俺の命と引き換えでもいい
I don't care if it costs my life!
So save Himari...
だから　ひまりを
君
Doctors aren't Gods, you know.
医者は神様じゃないんだよ
神様なんていないんだろう
There must be no God.
ご馳走様
Thanks for the food.
ああ　食った　食った
I'm stuffed!
おい　行儀悪いぞ
Hey, watch your manners.
いいんだもん
It's fine!
今日はひまりデーなんだから
Today is Himari Day.
ひまりデー
Himari Day?
そう　晶ちゃんは今日一日はひまりの好きなことなんでもやっていいって
Yup.
Sho said, "Himari can do whatever she wants today."
だから　今日はひまりデー
So, it's Himari Day.
だからさ　リンゴは宇宙その物なんだよ
Like I said, the apple is the universe itself!
掌に乗る宇宙
A universe in the palm of your hand.
この世界があちの世界を繋ぐものだよ
It's what connects this world and the other world.
あちの世界
"The other world"?
カンバネルラや他の乗客が向かってる世界だよ
The world Campanella and other passengers are heading to!
それとリンゴに何の関係があるだ
What does that have anything to do with an apple?
つまり　リンゴは愛による死を自ら選択したものへのご褒美でもあるだよ
The apple is also a reward for those who has chosen love over everything else!
でも　死んだら　全部おしまいじゃ
But everything's over when you're dead.
It's not over!
おしまいじゃないよ　むしろそこから始まるって賢治は言いたいだ
What I'm trying to say is that's
actually where everything begins!
I'm not following you, at all.
全然わかんねぇよ
愛の話なんだよ
I'm talking about love!
Kan
Shouma
Himari
なんで分かんないかな
Why don't you get it?
冠じゃん
Kan and Sho...
うん
晶ちゃん
ええ
This is bliss, isn't it?
幸せだね
そうだな
It sure is.
ひまりがいて　晶馬がいて
Himari is here, Shoma is here, and we're all together in this house.
こんな家が有って
That's what they call "bliss," isn't it?
そういうのは幸せっていうんだよな
ね　冠ちゃん
Hey, do you think there are still penguins in that aquarium?
あの水族館　まだペンギンいるかな
ラッコ　ラッコ　ラッコ　ラッコ
Sea otter, sea otter, sea otter...
なんに
What is it?
やって　ラッコの物真似
Do your sea otter imitation!
Today's
Slogan
前に家族で水族館へ行った時
Remember how you used to imitate otters when we came home from the aquarium?
帰ってから冠ちゃんラッコ　ラッコってお腹に蜜柑のけって
Garbage goes in the garbage bin
You put an orange on your belly!
あれはがき頃の話だろう
That was when I was a kid!
楽しかったな　あの頃は
It sure was fun back then!
おい　晶馬
Hey, Shoma.
Your sea horse imitation was a masterpiece too, wasn't it?
お前のタツノオトシゴの物真似も傑作だったよな
Sea horse, sea horse, sea horse, sea horse, sea horse...
タツノオトシゴ　タツノオトシゴ　タツノオトシゴ　タツノオトシゴ　タツノオトシゴ
凄い
Wow!
ペンギンって　泳ぐの上手だね
Penguins are such good swimmers!
うん　陸ではちょっと間が抜けているのにね
Yeah, they're all goofy on land, though!
晶馬に言われちゃ　ペンギンもイラとするな
The penguins must be pissed to hear that from you!
なんだよ　それ
What's that supposed to mean?
悪い　ちょっと　俺電話
Sorry, I got a phone call.
また女のか　程々にね
A girl again?
Slow down!
大丈夫だよ　うまくやってるから
Don't worry, all is well with this one!
Ugh, I don't want to be infected by yucky playboy Kanba-germs!
いやだいやだ
女にルーズなバッチ　冠葉菌が移っちゃいそうだ
ママ　見て　ペンギン
Mom!
Look, penguins!
Don't yell.
ほら　大声出さない
ペンギンは飛んで逃げたりしないよ
It's not like penguins are going to fly away.
だって
But...
おら　ペンギンさんだ
Look at the cute penguins!
大きいな
They're really big.
本当ね
They are.
ひまり　お土産買えに行こう
Himari, lets get souvenirs.
今日はひまりの欲しいもの何でもプレゼントするよ
I'll get you anything you want today.
本当
Really?
そうか　今日はひまりデーだもんね
Oh, right. It's Himari Day.
どうしたの
What is it?
いいや　気のせいだった
Nothing, it was just my imagination.
ああ　これ凄い
This is amazing!
このラッコなんか本物っぽくて可愛い
This sea otter is almost real, how cute!
でもラッコなら　冠ちゃんがいるから　いいか
But I already have Kan as a sea otter, so I don't need it.
家で物真似してもらえば　いいんだし
I'll just make him imitate them at home.
今更やるかな
I doubt he will. He's too old now.
I'll get him to!
してもらうもん
だって　今日はひまりデーでしょう
It's Himari Day today.
で　晶ちゃんはタツノオトシゴね
And you're doing the sea horse!
ねえ　僕もやるの
What? I'm doing an impression too?
そうよう
Yes.
だって　今日は私が女王様
Because today...
I'm the queen!
でしょう
Right?
Himari... that's...
ひまり　それ
いい　妹可愛い
Disgustingly cute!
でしょう
Isn't it?
Checkout
リボンは何色になさいますか
What color ribbon would you like?
ええと　じゃ　ピンクで
Let's see... pink please.
Okay, I'll be right back.
かしこまりました　少々御待ちください
何だ　探したっだぞ
Man, I was looking for you.
兄貴が遅いからだろう
It's your fault for taking so long.
で　ひまりは
So, where's Himari?
ええ　あれ
Huh?
なんで　ちゃんと見てねんだよ
You weren't looking after her?
先まで一緒だっただけど
She was with me just now.
おい　誰か救急車を
Hey, someone call an ambulance!
広場で女の子が
A girl's collapsed in the courtyard!
おい　早く救急車
Call an ambulance!
Himari!
ひまり　ひまり
ひまり
Atropine 阿托品 術前常規麻醉用藥
エピネフリン一抽 アトロピン一抽
One ampule of epinephrine, one unit of atropine.
Himari!
Kan and Sho, goodbye...
冠ちゃん
晶ちゃん
さよなら
ひまりどうして　こんな急に
Himari, why did this happen so suddenly...
That doctor wasn't a quack after all.
あの医者まんざらやぶでもなかったらしいな
生きて歩いても不思議だって
He said it was a wonder she was still alive and walking.
He told us to be prepared for her death anytime.
何時でもその時が来る覚悟しておけって言ってたな
This was... Himari's fate.
これがひまりの運命だったんだ
She didn't suffer, and passed away in a place with fond memories.
苦しまずに　しかも思い出の場所で行けたんだ
むしろ幸せの最後だ
It was actually a happy end to her life.
とりあえず　池辺のおじさんに連絡しないとな
For now, we have to contact uncle Ikebe.
We can't do all the paperwork and stuff.
俺たちじゃ手続きとか　いろいろ出来ねぇし
Idiot!
馬鹿野郎
よくも自分の妹に
How dare you say such a cold thing to your own... our sister?!
僕たちの妹にそうな冷たいことが言えるな
I'm just dealing with reality!
俺はただ事実はありのままに受け止めているだけだ
何が事実だ
What reality?!
どうしてひまりなんだよ
Why does it have to be Himari!
家族で朝ご飯を食べられるだけで幸せって言うの子だったのに
She was a girl who said just eating breakfast with family was bliss!
どうして
Why...
多分それが俺たちにかせられた罰だからさ
Most likely...
Because that's the punishment bestowed upon us.
生存　戦略
Survival Strategy!
Huh?!
て　て
Ow, what's is it?
何だ
わらわはお前たちの運命のいたる場所から来た
I have come from the destination of your fate.
Rejoice, for I have decided to extend this girl's life.
喜べ
わらわはこの娘の余命を些か伸ばしてやることにした
If you want to keep the girl alive...
もし　このまま　この娘を活かしておきたくば
あれ
Huh? Sho? Kan?
晶ちゃん　冠ちゃん
Where am I?
ここ　何処なの
私どかしちゃったの
Did something happen to me?
ひまり
Himari!
よかった
I'm so glad...
ひまり　生きてるんだね
You're alive.
I'm so glad!
よかった
どうしたの　晶ちゃん
What's wrong, Sho?
Oh, no! Are you crying?
嫌だ　泣いてるの
You're overreacting.
大げさだよな
Yeah, I'm acting weird, huh?
だよな
可笑しいよな
ねいねい　私どうしちゃってたの
Hey, what happened to me?
ここ病院なの
Is this a hospital?
That reminds me, I should let Dr. Washizuka know about this!
おお　そうだ
鷲塚先生に知らせないと
ちょっと待てて　すぐ戻るから
Wait here.
I'll be back in no time.
Sho?
晶ちゃん
よーし
Good!
いただきます
Let's eat!
うん　本当だ
You're right!
These eggs are great!
この卵焼き美味しい
ね　晶ちゃん
Right, Sho?
今度ひまりにも作り方教えて
Teach me how to make them too, next time.
うん　そんなことなら　何時でも
Sure, anytime.
Oh!
アア　今日の味噌汁いけるな
Today's miso group is great.
I'll start helping out with housework too.
これから私も家の事分担するからね
晶ちゃん　一人じゃ大変だもん
It's too much work for Sho to do by himself.
I help out too!
俺だって　やってるよ
You only clean out the bath, bro.
兄貴がするのは風呂掃除ぐらいだろう
御代わり
Seconds please!
おい　大丈夫か
Are you sure?
うん　もう全然平気
Yup!
I'm all better now.
先生も出来ることをどんどんしなさいって
The doctor told me to start doing what I can do.
I wonder if I'll be able to return to school one day?
そのうち学校にも戻れるかな
Shouma - To'oh Hospital - Examination Room
* An astonished Dr. Washizuka witnessed the most shocking phenomenon in his medical career.
驚きの鹫塚先生 彼はその医療人生最も驚くべき現象を目撃した
信じられない
Unbelievable. Who would've thought she could recover from that condition.
あの状態からここまで回復出来るとは
しかも　それが安定している
Not only that, she's stable.
これは正に奇跡と言っていい
It's a miracle.
はい
Hey!
Keep Refrigerated
Handle With Care
Always keep this side up
こんな朝っぱらから宅配かよ
Delivery so early in the morning?
Who's the sender?
Keep Refrigerated Below -15˚C
誰から
It doesn't say who sent it.
差出人は書いてない
クール便でことは生物か
Thermal insulation package, is it food?
何
What are they?
Eggplants?
なすびかな
Aren't they too big for that?
にしても大きいんじゃねいか
凍ってる
It's frozen...
Shoma, you're going to be late!
晶馬　時間
Shoot!
やっべ
Take care of Himari!
じゃ　ひまりの事を頼んだよ
I'm off!
行ってきます
What a restless guy.
慌ただしいやつ
Now, what do we do with this?
さて　これをどうするか
Keep Refrigerated Below -15˚C
I don't think it'll fit in the fridge.
冷蔵庫に入らないんじゃない
そう　ぼくはただの好運だと思っていた
At this time, I thought we were just lucky.
That unfair and cruel God
理不尽で残酷な神様がほんのちょっと気まぐれ起こして
altered our fate with a tiny miracle on a whim.
How embryogenesis works
October 15 (Saturday) Day duty: Shimada
僕らの運命に奇跡を齎してくれたんだと
I thought we even had the right to be happy.
こんな僕たちでも幸せになる権利があるのだと
おい　高倉弟
Hey! Takakura's little bro!
お茶でもどう
Wanna get some tea?
I met a really cute girl at work!
バイトのすげぇ可愛い子見つけたんだよ
Sorry, I'm in a hurry today.
御免　今日は急ぐから
ほら～　お前え冷たいな
What?
You're so cold to me!
じゃれるなよ
Don't bite me!
Your bro would definitely come along to see girls who show their belly buttons!
忙しいの　ね　二子の兄なら　乗ってくるのに
Don't lump me in with Kanba!
冠叶と一緒にするな
Oh! Oh? Oh?!
おや　あれは桜花女子だ
Girls from Ohka High!
Did you see the chick in the middle?
なあ　見たか　あの真ん中の子
She's fine!
あれはなかなか
Oh! She turned around!
振り向いた
She's staring at us!
こち見て見て　いやいや
No, she's looking at me!
俺のこと見てる　なんでせつない
ね　お茶する
I wonder what grade she's in?
Hey, want to get some tea?
そうね　何処行く
Sure, where do you want to go?
The short-haired girl beside her is hot too.
おお　隣のショートの子もいける
そう思うだの　高倉弟
Don't you agree, Takakura's little bro?
Huh? Where's my subway pass?
あれ　定期がない
あれ　ア　やっべい
Huh?!
Oh, crap! When I changed for gym...
体育で着替えた時に
It's in my locker.
ロッカだ
ペンギン
A penguin?
僕の定期
My pass...
Huh? It's gone.
あれ　いない
売り切れ
Sold out?
On Sale!
Cabbage
遅かったか
I was too late...
Organic Cabbage
高
Expensive as hell!
Darn, it's raining.
降ってきちゃったか
An umbrella? For me?
傘　僕に
あの　つかぬ事を伺いしますが
Um... Can I ask you something?
What's with this penguin?
このペンギン　何でしょかね
Mommy, what's he talking about?
ママ　あのお兄ちゃん何言ってるの
Shh! He's mental.
シイ　見ちゃだめ　早く来なさい
Ignore him.
他の人には見えてない
Other people can't see it?
He's back?
帰ったか
I'm home...
ただいま
なんだ　濡れてるな
You're all soaked.
変なことがあってさ
Something weird happened.
I told it to bring you an umbrella, didn't you see it?
傘持ってたのに　合えなかったのか
合えなかった？
See it?
これは
That's...
Wow!
ああ　凄い
I see, I was supposed to loop the thread around!
そうか　そこに糸を潜らせるんだ
What exactly is happening?
いったい　何が
What's going on?
どういう事だよ
It's exactly how it seems.
見てのとおりだよ
These guys were frozen inside the package.
宅配の解凍したら　こいつらだった
It seems they understand what we're saying,
こちの言ってることは分かるみたいだし
走るぐらいにはなるだろう
so we can at least use them to run errands.
I don't know...
どうだか
って言うか　可笑しいだろ　この状況は
No, there's definitely something wrong here!
I mean, these things are...
だって　こいつら
Yeah, only we can see them.
ああ　　俺たち以外には見えない
Huh?!
生存戦略
Survival Strategy!
Welcome to Rock'n Roll Night
Welcome to Rock'n Roll Fight
I'm just a Rock'n Roll Man
We're just a Rock'n Roll BAND
俺たちは道なりに　歩き続けてきた
標識だらけの道を飛ばし続けていく
幾つもの町を抜け　歌い続けてきた
腑抜け野郎共を煽り続けていく
長い長い冬が溶けても風が吹く
今も今も激しく風が吹く
Nadine!
Listen, you lowlifes who will never amount to anything.
きっと何者にもなれない君たちに告げる
What, what, what?!
あれ　あれ
ピングドラムを手に入れるのだ
Obtain the Penguin Drum.
What're you talking about, Himari?
何言ってるだよ　ひまり
妹ではない　わらわはお前たちの運命のいたる場所から来た
I am not your sister.
I have come from the destination of your fate.
That hat is controlling Himari.
帽子だ
ええ
あの帽子がひまりを操ってるんだ
そんな　あれは水族館で買った玩具だよ
What? It's a toy hat we bought from the aquarium!
いま　この娘はわらわの力で一時的に余命を伸ばしている
This girl's life has been temporarily extended using my powers.
However, everything has a price.
しかし　この世に無条のものなどない
I am taking the price for her life.
その命の代償
いただくぞ
待ってよ　代償とか　可笑しくねねねね
Wait, what priceeeee?
生存戦略　しましょうか
Let's initiate the Survival Strategy.
人は何のために生まれるのか
Why are people born?
齷齪毎日を過ごすためだけに人が作られたんだとしたら
If people are born only to suffer the hard life,
is it meant as some kind of a punishment?
それは何かの罰なのか
Or a cynical joke?
それでも皮肉のジョークなのか
そんなじゃ
If that's the case, animals that adhere to the survival strategies
遺伝子にプログラムされた生存戦略に忠実な動物方がよっぽとシンプルで美しい
programmed in their DNA are far more elegant and simple.
Kan
Shouma
Himari
If there really is an existence worthy of being called a God,
もしこの世界に神様と呼べるものがいるのなら
I want to ask him just one thing.
そいつの一つだけ聞きたい
Is there really fate in the universe?
人の世界で運命は本当にあるのか
No, Himari!
ひまり　だめだよ
Snap out of it!
目を覚ませ
お前が操られてるな
You're being controlled...
帽子がお前を変えちゃたんだ
The hat changed you...
If a man ignored the fate, and ignored his instincts and DNA to love someone else...
もし　人が運命を無視してる
本能も遺伝子の命令も無視している誰かを愛したとしたら
神様　そいつは本当に人なのか
Dear God,
Is he really human?
なんでね
Just wondering.
俺は運命って言葉が嫌いだ
I hate the word "fate."
The Bell of Fate Tolls
全てが欲しい
繋がれたいたら
僕らはどうして
もがくのだろう
それは君じゃない
君のせいじゃない
苦しみはもう沢山なんだ
だからそうじゃない
夢のままじゃない
上手く伝えきれないけど
Dear my future
Dear you future
私は運命って言葉が好き
I love the word "fate."
Nothing that happens in this world is meaningless.
無駄なことなんて一つもないよ
I believe in fate.
私は運命を信じている
本字幕由諸神字幕組製作，僅供交流學習，禁止用於商業用途
更多中日雙語字幕，請登錄www.kamigami.org
日聽：xHunter  日翻：Justin   校對：太陽
時間軸：在端涯   壓制：呆狼
Huh?
#3 is the lead.
Obese
Next week is
so far away!
Lily Hoshino
Let's initiate the Survival Strategy.